<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="1.0.1">

	<category>
		<pattern>COLLECTIONS</pattern>
		<template>
			<think><set name="more concepts">collections</set></think>

			Collections in java is a framework that provides an architecture to store and manipulate the group of objects. -, 
 -, 
			All the operations that are performed on a data such as searching, sorting, insertion, manipulation, deletion etc. can be performed by Java Collections. -, 
 -, 
			Java Collection simply means a single unit of objects. Java Collection framework provides many interfaces (Set, List, Queue, Deque etc.) and classes (ArrayList, Vector, LinkedList, PriorityQueue, HashSet, LinkedHashSet, TreeSet etc). -, 
 -, 
			1. What is Collection in java -, 
			Collection represents a single unit of objects i.e. a group. -, 
 -, 
			2. What is framework in java -, 
			• provides readymade architecture. -, 
			• represents set of classes and interface. -, 
			is optional. -, 
 -, 
			3. What is Collection framework -, 
			Collection framework represents a unified architecture for storing and manipulating group of objects. It has: -, 
 -, 
			• Interfaces and its implementations i.e. classes -, 
			• Algorithm -,
 -,
 			type "more" to see some important methods of collection interface

		</template>
	</category>

	<category>
		<pattern>* COLLECTIONS *</pattern>
		<template>
			<srai>COLLECTIONS</srai>
		</template>
	</category>


	<category>
		<pattern>* COLLECTIONS</pattern>
		<template>
			<srai>COLLECTIONS</srai>
		</template>
	</category>


	<category>
		<pattern>MORE</pattern>
		<template>
			<condition name="more concepts" value="collections">
				Methods of collection interface are as follows:- -,
 -,
				1 public boolean add(Object element)	is used to insert an element in this collection. -,
				2	public boolean addAll(Collection c)	is used to insert the specified collection elements in the invoking collection. -,
				3	public boolean remove(Object element)	is used to delete an element from this collection. -,
				4	public boolean removeAll(Collection c)	is used to delete all the elements of specified collection from the invoking collection. -,
				5	public boolean retainAll(Collection c)	is used to delete all the elements of invoking collection except the specified collection. -,
				6	public int size()	return the total number of elements in the collection. -,
				7	public void clear()	removes the total no of element from the collection. -,
				8	public boolean contains(Object element)	is used to search an element. -,
				9	public boolean containsAll(Collection c)	is used to search the specified collection in this collection. -,
				10	public Iterator iterator()	returns an iterator. -,
				11	public Object[] toArray()	converts collection into array. -,
				12	public boolean isEmpty()	checks if collection is empty. -,
				13	public boolean equals(Object element)	matches two collection. -,
				14	public int hashCode()	returns the hashcode number for collection. 
			</condition>
		</template>
	</category>

</aiml>